Ei Pa Pa Pe-Than

eipa [at] cmu [dot] edu | https://eipapa.github.io/ | @eipa01 | Google Scholar | Research Gate | GitHub

Research Interests and Approach

My research interests span computer-supported cooperative work (CSCW), science and technologies studies (STS), and critical human-computer interaction (HCI), and especially how to develop, maintain, and evolve a distributed decentralized software system that builds on a novel and sophisticated coordination model that addresses reinterpretability, resilience, and scalability.

I use case study research approach to address complex socio-technical questions, which includes ethnography (interviews and non-participant observations), archival analysis, quantitative collection of log and trace data with Python, SQL, and R, and a combination of all of these methods (mixed-methods) as appropriate and relevant.

Education

Carnegie Mellon U	Jniversity Pittsburgh, PA, USA
2017 - present	Postdoctoral Researcher Advisor: James Herbsleb, Institute for Software Research, School of Computer Science Topic: Coordination in time-bounded events (hackathons, datathons, etc.) for science, innovation, learning, and community building, and collaborative writing on GitHub
Nanyang Technolo	ogical University Singapore, Singapore
2010 - 2016	Doctor of Philosophy in Information Systems Advisor: Dion Hoe-Lian Goh and Chei Sian Lee, Wee Kim Wee School of Communication and Information Thesis: Investigating user-centered human computation games: The role of perceived enjoyment and its antecedents
2008 - 2009	Master of Science in Information Systems
•	puter Studies

Employment

Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh, PA, USA

2017 - present

Postdoctoral Researcher

Advisor: James Herbsleb, Institute for Software Research, School of

Computer Science

Topic: Coordination in time-bounded events (hackathons, datathons, etc.) for science, innovation, learning, and community building, and collaborative

writing on GitHub

2015 - 2016 Research Associate and Part-time Lecturer

NCS Singapore, Singapore

2009 - 2010 **Application Consultant** (Software Developer)

2005 - 2007 **Tutor**

Research Funding

NTU Doctoral Research scholarship

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Duration: August 2010 - August 2014

Amount: S\$ 111,600

Grant for Research Student

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Duration: 2011 – 2014 Amount: \$\$ 2,800

Conference Travel Grant

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Year: 2016

Amount: S\$ 1,000

Publications

Referred Journal Publications

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. "Corporate Hackathons, How and Why? A Multiple Case Study of Motivation, Project Proposal and Selection, Goal Setting, Coordination, and Project Continuation." [First round of revisions submitted to Human-Computer Interaction Journal]

- 2. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. "Collaborative Writing at Scale: Investigation of Pull-Based Model on GitHub." [Under the review of CSCW 2020]
- 3. Nolte, A., **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "You Hacked and Now What?: Exploring Outcomes of a Corporate Hackathon." In *Proceedings of the ACM on Human Computer Interaction, 2* (CSCW'18), Article 129, 23 pages. https://doi.org/10.1145/3274398
- 4. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "Designing Corporate Hackathons with a Purpose." *IEEE Software*, *36* (1), 15-22. https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863

Referred Conference Publications

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.** and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Understanding Hackathons for Science: Collaboration, Affordances, and Outcomes." In *Taylor N., Christian-Lamb C., Martin M., Nardi B. (eds) Information in Contemporary Society, iConference'19. Lecture Notes in Computer Science, vol 11420 (iConference'19), pp. 27-37. Springer, Cham. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-15742-5 3*

Referred Short Publications

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "Collaborative Writing on GitHub: A Case Study of a Book Project." In *Companion of the 2018 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (CSCW'18)*, pp. 305-308. https://doi.org/10.1145/3272973.3274083

Referred Workshop Publications

1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Herbsleb, J.D., Nolte, A., Gerber, E., Fiore-Gartland, B., Chapman, B., Moser, A., and Wilkins-Diehr, N. (2018). "The 2nd Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events: Current Trends and Next Steps in Research and Event Design." In *Extended Abstracts of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* (CHI EA'18), paper W35, 8 pages. https://doi.org/10.1145/3170427.3170615

Selected Other Publications

- 1. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Momcheva, I., Tolleud, E., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Hackathons for Science, How and Why?" *Poster presented at the 233rd Meeting of the American Astronomical Society, AAS Meeting* #233, id.459.11. https://ui.adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2019AAS...23345911P/abstract
- 2. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Dabbish, L., and Herbsleb, J.D. (2019). "Collaborative Writing at Scale: A Case Study of Two Open-Text Projects Done on GitHub." *Paper presented at the 7th ACM*

- Conference on Collective Intelligence 2019 (CI'19). https://ci.acm.org/2019/assets/ proceedings/CI 2019 paper 65.pdf
- 3. Powell, J., Hayden, L., Nolte, A., Herbsleb, J.D., **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Wong, M., Kalyanam, R., Ellet, K., Pamidighantam, S., Traxler, K., and Cannon, A. (2018). "An Analysis of the PEARC 2018 Science Gateways Community Institute Hackathon: Lessons Learned." *Poster presented at Gateways 2018 organized by the Science Gateways Community Institute (SGCI)*. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.7070309.v2
- 4. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, and Nolte, A. (2018). "The 2nd Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events." *Technical Report CMU-ISR-18-109, Carnegie Mellon University*. http://eipapa.github.io/files/ISR-techreport-2018.pdf
- 5. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Nolte, A., Filippova, A., Bird, C., Scallen, S. and Herbsleb, J.D. (2018). "An Empirical Study of Team Familiarity, Goal Setting, and Process in Time-Bounded Events." *Poster presented at the 13th Annual Interdisciplinary Network for Group Research Conference (INGRoup'18).*
- 6. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2017). "Does it matter how you play? The effects of collaboration and competition among players of human computation games." *Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology, 68* (8), 1823-1835. https://doi.org/10.1002/asi.23863
- 7. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D. H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2016). "Personality, motivations, and information quality: A comparative study across games for human computation." In *Proceedings of the Association for Information Science and Technology (ASIS&T'16), 53* (1), 1-10. https://doi.org/10.1002/pra2.2016.14505301049
- 8. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2015). "A typology of human computation games: An analysis and a review of current games." *Behaviour and Information Technology*, *34* (8), 809-824. https://doi.org/10.1080/0144929X.2013.862304
- 9. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D. H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2015). "The effects of collaboration and competition on players' perceptions in human computation games." In *Proceedings of the 17th International Conference on Asia-Pacific Digital Libraries (ICADL'15)*, pp. 246-251, Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-27974-9 25
- 10. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D.H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2014). "Making work fun: Investigating antecedents of perceived enjoyment in human computation games for information sharing." *Computers in Human Behavior, 39* (2014), 88-99. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chb.2014.06.023
- 11. **Pe-Than, E.P.P.**, Goh, D. H.-L., and Lee, C.S. (2012). "Enjoyment of a mobile information sharing game: Perspectives from needs satisfaction and information quality." In *Proceedings of 14th International Conference on Asia-Pacific Digital Libraries (ICADL'12)*, pp. 126-135, Springer Berlin Heidelberg. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-34752-8_16

Teaching

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Instructor		
CI6221	Information Visualization (cross-listed, graduate)	Aug 2016
CI6228	Managing Information Systems (graduate)	Jan 2016
IN9008	Digital Social Games for Organizations (undergraduate)	Jan 2015

Teaching Assistant

IN9006	Social Computing and Applications (graduate)	Jan 2014
CS2008	Fundamentals of Research (undergraduate)	Aug 2013
CI6208	Research Methods and Data Analysis for Information Professionals (graduate)	Jan 2013
CI6222	Mobile & Ubiquitous Applications (graduate)	Aug 2012

University of Computer Studies, Yangon

Tutor

Fundamentals of Data Structures (undergraduate)	2006-2007
Operating Systems (undergraduate)	2006-2007

Professional Services

Reviewing

2020	ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems
	iConference
2019	ACM CSCW: ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work
	ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems
	iConference
2018	ACM CHI: ACM Conference on Computer-Human Interaction
	ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems
	iConference
2017	ACM CHI: ACM Conference on Computer-Human Interaction
	Journal of Information Science Theory and Practice
2016	Cyberpsychology, Behavior, and Social Networking
	Aslib Journal of Information Management

2015 ECIS: European Conference on Information Systems

Organizing

2019	World of Code (WoC) hackathon, Carnegie Mellon University	
2018	Science Gateways Hackathon by the Science Gateways Community Institute (SGCI), PEARC18 Conference, Wyndham Grand Pittsburgh	
2018	ACM Workshop on Hacking and Making at Time-Bounded Events: Current Trends and Next Steps in Research and Event Design, ACM CHI'18, Montreal, Canada	

Volunteering

2016	Student Volunteer, The 66th Annual Conference of the International Communication Association (ICA)
2011-2013	Student Assistant, Graduate Admission Exercise, Wee Kee Wee School of Communication and Information
2011	Student Volunteer, International Conference on Social Informatics (SocInfo2011)

Professional Associations

ACM	Association for C	Computing Machinery
I I CIVI	1 1330 Clauon for C	Joinpumiz Macimici y

ACM SIGCHI Special Interest Group on Computer–Human Interaction

ACM SIGSOFT Special Interest Group on Software Engineering
ASIS&T Association for Information Science & Technology